Now we've gathered the data and made a few assessments.
الآن قمنا بجمع البيانات وقمنا بإجراء بعض التقييمات.
The few is important. We don't need to
القلة مهمة. لا نحتاج إلى
identify every issue right from the start. We can iterate.
تحديد كل مشكلة منذ البداية. يمكننا التكرار.
So now we can start cleaning.
لذا، يمكننا الآن أن نبدأ التنظيف.
Cleaning means acting on the assessments we made to improve quality and tidiness.
التنظيف يعني العمل على التقييمات التي أجريناها لتحسين الجودة والترتيب.
Improving quality doesn't mean changing the data to make it say something different.
لا يعني تحسين الجودة تغيير البيانات لجعلها تُظهر شيئًا مختلفًا.
That would be data fraud.
لأن هذا سيعد تزوير في البيانات.
Instead, we're talking about things like correcting it when it's
وبدلاً من ذلك، نتحدث عن أشياء أخرى مثل تصحيحها عندما تكون
inaccurate or removing data when it's wrong or irrelevant.
غير دقيقة أو إزالة البيانات عندما تكون خاطئة أو ليست ذات صلة.
Yeah, or replacing, like filling in missing values;
نعم، أو استبدالها، مثل استكمال القيم المفقودة،
or merging, like combining gather datasets that were split up.
أو دمجها، مثل الجمع بين مجموعات البيانات التي تم تقسيمها.
All of this stuff can be done manually,
يمكن القيام بكل هذه الأشياء يدويًا،
but it's most efficiently done using code that minimizes repetition.
إلا أنه يتم إجراؤها بكفاءة باستخدام التعليمة البرمجية التي تقلل التكرار.
Improving tidiness means transforming the dataset so that each variable is a column,
تحسين الترتيب يعني تحويل مجموعة البيانات بحيث يكون كل متغير عمودًا،
each observation is a row,
وكل ملاحظة صف،
and each type of observational unit is a table.
وكل نوع من وحدة الملاحظة عبارة عن جدول.
There are special functions of Pandas that help us do that.
تحتوي Pandas دوال خاصة تساعدنا على القيام بذلك.
We'll dive deeper into those in Lesson Four of the course.
سنتعمق أكثر في هذه الدوال في الدرس الرابع من الدورة التدريبية.